DEVIKA PARANJPE

• Pune, INDIA • C: +917709022879 • dpmp1986@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

5 years as **Backend/FullStack Developer** with core skills as **AWS** (Solutions Architect Associate certified), Python, Django, Flask, REST API, JavaScript, GO, PostgreSQL with the additional **4 years** of experience in **Software Testing** (manual). Looking for the relevant remote opportunities.

KEY SKILLS

• Languages: Python, Go, REST API, JavaScript

• Framework/Tools: Django, Flask, Git, Jira, Jenkins

• Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL

• Cloud Platforms: AWS, Digital Ocean

WORK HISTORY

Staff Cloud Consultant – Python Apps Associates (I) Pvt. Ltd. (Remote)

04/2022 to present

- Development of REST API's, Automation in Python, Django. Deployment on AWS production server. Third party api integrations includes, **boto3**, **Jenkins**, **Zabbix**
- Managing the AWS automation integrations on Production and Development servers.
- Received appreciation from Supervisors in first 6 months from joining with 4.3/5 rating at work.
- Mentoring Juniors in assigning task and code development

Senior Product Developer – Python Zekardo Automotive Solutions (Startup), Gurgaon

04/2020 to 04/2022

- As a Full stack developer lead project development, deployment and management. Actively involved in Clients meet, technical business discussions and required optimizations.
- Helped organization in setting up complete project in latest TechStack which in turn increased sales and received funding from Investors.
- Full stack development using Python, Django Framework, Postgresql. HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Jquery. Deployed the application on AWS EC2
- Integrated payment gateway Paytm, TextLocal SMS, Calendly and other third-party tools
- Received appreciation comments like "Excellent Work Ethics"

Freelance Python Developer Upwork Global Inc.

04/2017 to 12/2018 and 06/2019 to 03/2020

- Worked on Python Networking project with client from USA
- Full stack development and deployment of project from scratch using Python Django, Flask, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL for a **Startup** in Gurgaon. Deployed on GoDaddy.
- Full Stack Development from scratch and deployment done on PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Cloud Platform- Digital Ocean
- Data mining and management from Bioinformatics databases: NCBI, Drugbank.
- Received appreciation from client: "Great Expert to work with" and many more mentioned on profile: https://www.upwork.com/fl/devikaparanjpe

Python Developer XEBRIUM Software Pvt. Ltd., Pune 02/2019 to 05/2019 (Had to leave due to relocation issues)

Developed REST API in Python, Django Rest Framework (class based). Backend PostgreSQL

Bioinformatics Industrial Trainee RASA Life Science Informatics, Pune, India

11/2016 to 05/2017 (Contractual 6 months)

• Development of automation tool in Perl language to fetch data from Bioinformatics databases

Full Stack Developer 01/2016 to 06/2016

RMK Technologies and Services, (Startup) Pune, India

- Full Stack Development in PHP, MySQI, HTML, CSS from scratch to deployment
- Integrated EBS payment gateway.
- Deployed on GoDaddy

Test Engineer 08/2010 to 06/2014

NTT DATA Global Delivery Services Limited, Pune, India

- Reviewing Business requirements. Test Case Writing and Reviewing using Test Link tool.
- Defects were tracked, reviewed, analyzed using Bugzilla, Jira.
- Scope of Testing: Requirements Testing, Integration Testing Functional Testing, Regression Testing. Experience of using version control system: SVN

EDUCATION

- Master of Science: Bioinformatics, 2015, from Bharti Vidyapeeth Deemed University, Pune
- Master of Computer Application, 2010 from Rani Durgavati University, Jabalpur

CERTIFICATION

- AWS AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate- SA-C03
- LinkedIn Learning Courses: Advanced Python, Statistics Fundamentals
- Indian Testing Board: ISTQB

ADDITIONAL

- Master in Indian Classical Dance "KATHAK" and train students for exam in this dance form.
- Intercollegiate and other competitions winner. Also performed on various occasions in India and USA.
- Learning KARATE Maroon belt.
- Passport and Visa: Holding valid passport and USA Tourist visa.
- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/devika-paranjpe-15885938/